Welcome to our training Ship and Fulfill using third-party apps.
Amazon sellers use a variety
of technologies to launch, manage, and grow their businesses.
Some stick to the tools available
in Seller Central.
They list using Add Products, ship using manage orders, and send inventory
to fulfillment centers using the Send to Amazon workflow.
Other sellers use third-party apps to
list, ship, fulfill, and perform a variety of other business operations.
You've probably used
apps before on a smartphone or tablet to complete a specific task, like rating a restaurant or
checking the weather.
Amazon sellers can also use the specialized functionality of apps to
streamline and scale their businesses.
We maintain a catalog of Amazon-approved apps in Seller Central
in the Selling Partner App Store.
You can visit the App Store anytime using the URL sellercentral.
amazon.
com/selling-partner-appstore.
On the home page, select an app category to browse or use the search bar to locate a specific app
by
name.
Click an app's icon to go to its detail page where you can review features and functionality.
We provide contact information and web links so you can quickly access and use apps.
Each app in the Selling Partner App Store is reviewed and authorized by Amazon.
The developers who publish in the App Store are vetted by Amazon too.
Some of the apps we list
integrate directly with Seller Central.
Others are standalone, but all the apps in the App Store
have access to the same kind of selling data you see in Seller Central.
Their access is secured
through one of our two API services.
Selling Partner API or SP API or our Legacy Service,
Marketplace Web Service, also called Amazon MWS.
Now that you know a little more about third-party
apps and where to find them, let's focus on apps that can help with FBA or fulfillment by Amazon
shipments.
We'll also review apps that can help with MFN or merchant-fulfilled orders.
Using an app to ship inventory or fulfill orders can offer several advantages.
An app with specific
features might help you create FBA shipments faster, or it could make it easier to purchase
shipping for MFN orders.
An app might also make printing labels, tracking shipments,
and packing items more intuitive.
To illustrate the range of shipping and fulfillment apps available
in the Selling Partner App Store, let's review three examples, ShipStation, ScanPower, and Shippo.
Note that these examples don't constitute recommendations from Amazon.
They're offered
here as information to help you explore all the third-party apps available in the App Store.
ShipStation provides sellers with features that support both MFN and FBA fulfillment.
You can use ShipStation to import MFN orders in bulk so you no longer have to copy and paste
information manually from Seller Central.
Or you can use ShipStation to compare carrier rates,
print shipping labels, and manage your buy shipping services from Amazon.
The app updates tracking information in real time too and makes it available to customers.
You can also use ShipStation to create FBA shipping labels and receive notifications on the status
of FBA shipments.
ScanPower helps simplify FBA shipments using a feature called Boxt.
You can use ScanPower to provide box content information for multiple shipments simultaneously.
It also allows you to scan and pack items while printing 2D barcodes for box content.
And it can warn you about incorrect items or quantities.
You can also use ScanPower to get packing history reports which can help track and enhance FBA
related operations.
Finally, Shippo helps sellers streamline and reduce costs for MFN orders.
You can use Shippo to find and compare discounted shipping rates across carriers.
You can use it to create business rules that print your shipping labels faster.
Shippo can also help you validate shipping addresses and avoid failed deliveries.
Additionally, Shippo can help you schedule pickups, customize shipping labels, and automate customer
notifications.
ShipStation, Boxt by ScanPower, and Shippo are just a small sample of the third-party
apps available in the Selling Partner App Store to help you ship and fulfill.
We encourage you to explore additional shipping and fulfillment apps for both FBA and MFN sellers
by clicking the Shipping Solutions category on the App Store home page.
On the next page,
use filters to find apps designed for specific programs or to search by star rating, language,
or store.
We also encourage you to explore apps in other categories that might help streamline
and scale your business.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon Store.